hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation playlist and
today we are going to discuss how we can
automate the save as dialog box which is
uh like a Microsoft Windows dialog box
and this cannot be steered like any
other web application uh because you
cannot scan this particular application
through the normal X engine right uh
since it's like a desktop based dialog
box so you need to use some other
modules now uh here uh as you can see
this dialog box appears whenever you are
trying to save any particular file it
could be any Microsoft Office file uh
like a Word document so if you want to
make some changes and after that you
want to save this file so basically you
need to steer all these elements right
so you need to enter the file name uh
the save as type uh then where do you
want to save this or what name you want
to put and then click on save or cancel
right so these kind of uh dialog boxes
can be steered okay using the save as uh
module which is part of the t-box
automation modules uh part of the
standard subset which comes uh with tosa
Commander so you can easy easily
automate this particular scenario using
that particular module so let's look how
you can do this okay so I am here uh in
my tosa test case section and I have
created a test case here called save
file so here I'm going to search and ADD
test step and then go to tbox save
as okay and then I'm going to add this
here and here you can see there are a
couple of module attributes uh which you
can call them as parameters for this
particular module so here uh the first
module attribute is caption okay so this
caption is basically U the caption of
the window which you want to steer uh it
could be mostly the title of the window
so for example here uh the caption of
this particular window is save as right
so we need to enter the same here so I'm
going to enter same as here so coming to
the second module attribute is the file
name label this what you see here so
this is the label of the file name right
um and if by default it is file name
then tosa will automatically steer it
you don't need to mention it separately
but if it is something else if it is a
some custom uh edit box then uh it has
got a different label then also you can
mention it but if you want you can still
mention this okay so so I can say file
name
here okay and then uh the file path so
where do you want to save this
particular file and that will be entered
right in the file name okay along with
the path you will have the name of the
file so uh we can enter this here the
file path so I'm going to enter this uh
c
training and then uh the file file name
actually
okay so I'm going to call it
test.
do
right so this will be saved here uh
under the training folder and then the
button so this button refers to uh all
the buttons in this particular dialog
box so either want to click on save or
cancel we want to click on save so I'm
going to do that now so I'm going to
write here save
right and then there are two more
attributes called confirmation popup
caption and Confirmation popup button
now these are basically the popups which
might appear after you click on Save
right so sometimes um some popup will
appear whether uh you have changing the
name of an existing file so it will ask
you for a confirmation or you are making
some other changes right so any popup
which uh comes up after you click on
Save could be handled with these two
attributes so again we need to provide
the caption and then uh we have to
provide the button name which we want to
click so I will tell you uh we'll see uh
what kind of popup comes up after we
perform this uh steps and then I will
tell you how you can uh enter the
remaining two attributes to handle that
popup
okay so let's go ahead and execute this
now
and as you can see uh it entered the
path okay and it clicked on Save but
after that there is a new popup from
Microsoft Word you can see that it is
mentioning your document will be
upgraded to a a new file format okay and
it is asking for your confirmation so
this is a popup uh which comes up right
uh we were not aware of this but uh if
it comes up then it can be handled using
the two
attributes okay so here uh we need to
provide a caption again so what's the
caption it's Microsoft
Word so I'm going to mention this
Microsoft
Word and then uh what button we want to
enter here right so we want to click on
okay to go over this so I'm going to say
okay
here right so these are uh the two
changes which we need to do here to save
this particular file now let's run this
complete uh test step again for that I
need to bring this back to the original
state okay so I'm going to click on
cancel and that will bring to this
particular savest dialog box it will not
be saved until you click on okay on that
particular pop up right so again um I
will going to run this complete step now
so that it runs through the whole step
okay so now you will see that uh this
file has been saved okay uh with the
name test. talk and in the exact
location where we mentioned it so it
went through all the steps right so this
is how you can easily uh automate any
save as stal box whenever it appears
maybe it is from your desktop
application or it is from some file
which you are trying to
automate that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video